そうやって 依存したまま
捨てられて 死んでいくんだ！
４日後 ８月15日
お前の死は
この世界によって 決められている
避けられやしない
You're going to die...
Abandoned, still longing...
だが… 俺は そんなの ごめんだ
あっ…
Four days. August 15th.
俺は 世界に あらがう！
はっ…
The world itself has decided that you will die.
まゆりを 必ず救ってみせる
There's no avoiding it.
あ…
But I won't let it happen.
I'll fight the world!
I will save Mayuri!
コインロッカー…
あっ
大ビル前…
IBN5100
The coin locker...
In front of the Daibiru.
The IBN 5100...
Finalize Apoptosis
岡部！ どうしたの？
Okabe, what's wrong?
はあっ はあっ…
はあっ よし これで！
Okay! This'll...
スト～ップ！
Stop!
コインロッカーに IBN5100が？
The IBN 5100 is in a coin locker.
萌郁が白状した！
まだ 回収されていないようだ
Moeka told me...
It hasn't been recovered yet.
で？
決まってるだろ！
So?
What else?
こいつで
ロッカーをぶち壊して…
I'll break the locker open with this!
落ち着いて！ よく思い出して
Calm down.
Remember...
何をだ！
Remember what?!
今までのこと
何度 Ｄメールを取り消しても
Everything that's happened.
Despite all the D-mails you've undone,
IBN5100は 手に入らなかった
あ…
you haven't recovered the IBN 5100.
多分 元の世界線に戻らない限り
無理なんだと思う
Most likely, it's impossible until you get back
to the original world line.
そして そのためには
順番どおりに やるしかない
And for that to happen,
you have to do things in order.
あ…
くっ… う…
すぐ目の前に あるっていうのに…
It's so close...
少なくとも 手がかりは つかんだ
But now, we have a clue.
あ…
桐生萌郁は ＦＢっていう人の
命令なら 従うのよね？
Kiryuu Moeka will do whatever this FB says, right?
その人が
ラウンダーの指揮官なんでしょ？
And FB's the... leader, right?
だったら…
Then...
あ…
IBN5100を見張っていれば
接触できるかもしれない！
If I stake out the IBN 5100, maybe I'll see them.
うん？
何しに来た？
What are you doing here?
Bread
あたしも ＦＢに会いたい
I want to see FB, too...
会いたくないんじゃ
なかったのか？
Didn't you want to avoid seeing them?
会えば幻滅させると
Because they'd hate you or something?
確かめたい ホントのこと
I want to know... the truth.
確かめて どうする？
What good will it do you?
分からない
I don't know.
俺が お前と一緒に
行動すると思ったのか？
Did you think I'd work with you?
う…
まあ…
話が通じないヤツではないか
Well, I guess I can talk to you.
はあ？
あっ どうしたの？
What's wrong?
あ… な 何でもない
N-Nothing.
桐生萌郁と 一緒にいる？
You're with Kiryuu Moeka?
どうして そうなるの？
だって その人…
Why?
She's...
とにかく そういうことだ
That's just how it worked out.
何か 動きがあったら連絡する
If something happens, I'll tell you.
ああ！ ちょっと こら！
Hey, wait!
まったく…
Jeez...
オカリン？
Was that Okarin?
え？ うん
Yeah.
う…
どうしたの？
What's wrong?
なんだか 最近… 全然 オカリンと
I feel like lately,
Okarin and I haven't talked at all.
お話ししてないような
気がするなぁって
あっ まゆりおねえちゃん！
Mayuri-oneechan!
あっ 綯ちゃん
Nae-chan!
トゥットゥル－！
助手のおねえちゃんも
Hi there, assistant-oneechan!
はあ… ｢紅莉栖｣おねえちゃんね
It's Kurisu-oneechan.
おお
どうも…
Hi there.
昨日は すみませんでした
Sorry about yesterday.
岡部に 家賃5,000円アップって
伝えといてくれ
Tell Okabe his rent's going up 5,000 yen.
あ… あ はい
そういや あの野郎
I-I will.
Actually, I haven't seen him today.
今日は 見なかったな
体でも壊したか？
Did he get sick or something?
バカは 風邪ひかねえって
いうけどな
Though they say idiots don't get sick...
あ… 実験に使う道具を
探し回ってるみたいで
I think he's looking for stuff
to use in his experiments.
実験ね… ったく 幸せな野郎だぜ
えっ？
Experiments, huh?
Lucky guy...
学生風情が 部屋なんぞ借りて
A student with his own damned room,
あんたらみたいな仲間がいて
friends like you guys,
好き勝手やって…
ホント 幸せだぜ
and who does whatever he wants...
He really is lucky.
だがよ…
お父さん 早くしないと
But...
Daddy, if we don't hurry, we'll miss the sale!
タイムサービス 終わっちゃうよ！
よ～し 行くか 綯！
うん！
Right! Let's go, Nae!
バイバイ おねえちゃんたち！
バイバ～イ！
Bye-bye, onee-chans!
Bye-bye!
今日の夕飯 何がいい？
What do you want for dinner?
う～ん… えっとね～
Um...
フフ
ウフフ
ＦＢからのメールか？
A message from FB?
うん…
見てもいいか？
えっ？
Can I see it?
あ… う…
｢Ｍ４の判断は
正しかったと思っているわ
"I think M4 was right.
I think M4 was right.
To be honest, no one works
as hard as M4.
正直な話 Ｍ４ほど
To be honest, no one works as hard as M4."
ひたむきに頑張ってくれる人は
いないわね｣
Ｍ４？
M4?
ＦＢが付けてくれた コードネーム
The code name FB gave me.
ＦＢと 私しか知らない
Only FB and I know it.
秘密の…
It's a secret.
｢あなたは 確かに
"That's true.
人づきあいが
苦手かもしれないわね Ｍ４
You may be bad at dealing with others, M4.
でも それは あなたの個性とも
いえるんじゃないかしら｣
But that's part of what makes you you."
おふくろさんか…
A mom, huh?
間違いない IBN5100！
That's it...
The IBN 5100!
じゃあ… あいつが ＦＢか
Then is he FB?
No.
違う ＦＢは 女の人
FB is a woman.
あっ！
あいつ！
I know him!
新宿 新宿に到着です…
今日
このあと バイトなんだよね～
ご注意ください
週末は きついね
ドアが 閉まります…
あっ！
お荷物 お引きください…
はっ あ… くっ！
しまった！
Damn it!
くっ…！
うっ あ…
What's wrong?
どうしたの？
後で 説明する！
I'll explain later.
うん？
えっ？
ミスター ブラウン…
Mister Braun?
ちなみに 運転は？
So, have you driven since you got your license?
ペーパー
No.
安全運転で頼む
Please drive safely.
あの男に 見覚えは？
Have you ever seen him before?
見たことない
No.
どういうことだ？
What does this mean?
４日後 ８月15日
Four days. August 15th.
お前の死は
この世界によって 決められている
The world itself has decided that you will die.
避けられやしない
There's no avoiding it.
A plane to France...
フランス行きの飛行機…
ＳＥＲＮがある国か
That's where SERN is.
ＦＢらしき女は 現れなかったな
う…
We never saw any women
who could have been FB.
うん？
連絡くらいしろ！
At least give me a damned phone call!
こっちも 立て込んでいたんだ
I was busy.
私は いい
Forget about me.
でも…
But...
Mayuri...
まゆりには…
あ…
Come to think of it,
そういえば もう随分
話していないような気がする
I think it's been a long time since we last spoke.
あの子も そう言ってた
That's what she said, too.
すまない
I'm sorry.
行くぞ
えっ？
Let's go.
直接 当たってみるしかない
We'll have to ask him directly.
Ask him...
当たってみるって…？
俺たちが
よく知っている人間にだ
Someone we know well.
うん？
おお どうした？ 朝っぱらから
What brings you here so early?
うん？ まあ 上がれや
Come in.
で？ 何の用だ
So, what do you want?
早速 値上げした分の家賃6,000円
払いにきたってか？
Did you come to pay the extra 6,000 yen
I added to your rent?
おいおい そこは お前 1,000円
増えてるじゃないですかって
Hey, hey... You're supposed to say,
"That's 1,000 more yen than you said!"
突っ込むところだろう
お聞きしたいことがあります
There's something I'd like to ask you.
What? Why so formal?
何だよ 改まって
ＦＢという人物について
You know someone named FB, don't you?
ご存じですね？
俺たちは 全部 見ていたんです
We saw it all.
ここから IBN5100が運ばれるのも
And the IBN 5100 being taken from here as well.
あなたを どうこうする気はない
We don't care about you.
俺たちは
ただ ＦＢに会いたいんです
We want to see FB.
教えてください
いったい どこにいるんですか？
Please tell me where they are.
裏切ったようだな Ｍ４
You sold us out, M4.
あっ！
はっ！
The code name FB gave me.
ＦＢが付けてくれた
コードネーム…
Only FB and I know it.
ＦＢと私しか知らない 秘密の…！
まさか…
どういうこと？
Then...
What do you mean?
｢フェルディナント ブラウン｣って
知ってるか？
Ever heard of Ferdinand Braun?
The Nobel laureate who invented the Braun tube.
ブラウン管を発明した
ノーベル物理学者…
さすがだな その頭文字は？
That's the guy.
And what are his initials?
Ｆ… Ｂ…
F... B...
じゃあ あなたが！
Then you're...
ああっ そんなの… ウソ…！
That can't be!
So you're following dependence
with reality avoidance?
依存の次は 現実逃避か
Nae is asleep.
綯が寝ている 場所を変えよう
Let's go somewhere else.
この町も
どんどん 変わっていきやがる
This town keeps changing.
本当に… ＦＢ？
ああ
Are you really FB?
Yes.
But those messages...
でも メールは…
全部 俺が書いた
I wrote them all.
はっ…
Why did I write like a woman?
なんで 女言葉かって？
お前を だますためさ
To trick you.
Bu-
そんな…
お前だけじゃないぜ
You weren't the only one.
I message the others, too,
ほかのヤツらにも
in the guise of whomever they most need.
そいつが 求めている人物像で
メールを送ってやるんだ
もっとも お前みたいなヤツが
一番 だましやすくて助かるがな
Of course, people like you are
the easiest to trick, which helps.
ああっ…
彼女との 連絡を絶ったのは？
Why break off contact with her?
IBN5100を手に入れた時点で
そいつは 用済みさ
The second she found the IBN 5100,
I didn't need her anymore.
So I stopped talking to her.
だから 捨てた
ダイレクトメールで
メンバーを集めんだよ
We collect members through text messages.
People like that are the easiest to deal with.
そういうヤツらは 扱いやすい
用が済めば 始末もしやすい
And the easiest to get rid of when we're done.
There's nothing they belong to.
もともと 居場所がねえような
ヤツらだからな
あなたが
ＳＥＲＮの犬だったなんて…
I can't believe you're SERN's dog...
犬？ フンッ
Dog?
鈴羽… 橋田 鈴さんは
そんなことをさせるために
Suzuha... Hashida Suzu-san
didn't take care of you for that!
あなたの世話をしたんじゃない！
お前…
なんで 鈴さんのこと知ってる？
How do you know about Suzu-san?
鈴さんには 関係ねえ
Suzu-san has nothing to do with this...
Not a thing!
鈴さんには 関係ねえことだ
だが！
But...
What do you know?!
お前たちに 何が分かる！
あっ…！
真冬の… マンホールの中で
寝たことあるか？
Ever sleep down a manhole,
in the middle of winter?
まだ ガキだった
I was still a kid.
コンクリが冷たくてな
骨に しみやがる
The concrete was so cold,
it seeps into your bones.
I didn't eat for three or four days at a time.
３日も ４日も 何も食べねえで
ずっと… 横になってると
And when I lay down,
来やがるんだよ
えっ？
they came.
ネズミが
死体と間違えて かじりに…
Rats. They thought I was dead,
and came to eat me.
ああっ…
んな時さあ 糸がたれてたんだ
And then, I saw a thread descend...
As thin as a spider's.
クモの糸
そしたら 上るしかねえだろ
I had no choice but to climb it...
Even if, at the top,
たとえ 行き着いた先で
I ended up dirtying my hands.
この手を
汚すことになったとしても
I kept climbing the thread.
そうやって 糸を上って…
気が付いたら 操り人形だ
And next thing I knew, I was a puppet on a string.
I couldn't escape.
逃れることなんか できねえ
糸から 逃れた人形は…
Puppets who escape the thread...
あっ…！
はっ…！
ああっ！
あっ！
あ あ… ああ…
裏切り者には死って やつだ
Traitors die.
ま 任務を完了しても 消されるが
Well, once you complete your mission, you also die.
You called me a dog, didn't you?
｢犬｣って 言ったな？
犬なんてもんじゃねえ
家畜さ 俺たちは
I'm worse than a dog.
I'm cattle.
逃げようと思ったこともあった
Sometimes, I thought of running.
こんな俺にも
大事なものが出来た
But I have something I care about now.
そいつを巻き込みたくねえって
I didn't want to involve them.
But failure isn't allowed.
だがよ 失敗は 許されねえ
If you run, they go after your family.
逃げようとすれば 家族も…
俺も 失敗した
I failed, too.
だが 綯は 何も知らねえ
But Nae doesn't know anything.
あっ
ああっ…！
As long as I die.
俺さえ 死ねば…
Wait—
待て！
あ あ… ああ…
うっ… うえ～
うえ～… ゲホッ ゲホッ…
O-Okabe-ku...
お… 岡部君…
あっ…
Okabe-kun...
岡部… 君…
I-I'm sorry.
ご… ごめん…
う…
I'm sorry.
ごめ… ん…
うっ…
O-Okabe... His phone!
お… 岡部 携帯！ Ｄメール！
The D-mail!
Okabe!
岡部！
はっ！
To: M4
Stop searching for the IBN 5100,
and return to stand by.
Do not act under any circumstances.
あ…
うん
ああっ！ あ…
萌郁…？
Moeka...
うん？
あっ
From: Shining Finger
Subject: No Subject
I won't need the IBN 5100 for a while.
Moeka
You won't need it?
必要ない…って
From: Shining Finger
Subject: No Subject
My boss said to stop looking for it.
Moeka
Yes, this is Urushibara.
はい 漆原です あっ 凶真さ…
Kyouma-sa—
えっ？ IBN5100？
What? An IBN 5100?
Yes.
それなら…
ああ…！
It's here...
あった…！ ああ…
Daru!
ダル！
橋田なら いないわよ
Hashida's not here.
コミマに行くって
言ってたじゃない
He said he was going to Comima.
頼む！ 俺の願いを聞いてくれ！
Please...
Hear my request!
おお？
うん？
I see...
なるほどね
まゆりの死を避けるには
To save Mayuri,
we need to get out of this alpha world line,
今 私たちがいる
α世界線から抜け出し
and return to the world line
before you sent the first D-mail,
岡部が 一番 最初のＤメールを
送る前の世界線
β世界線に 戻るしかない
the beta world line.
For that to happen, we have to erase
the information from SERN's database.
それには
ＳＥＲＮのデータベースにある
そのデータを消すしかないんだ
Mayushi dies, and Miss Amane
is my daughter from the future.
まゆ氏が死ぬとか
阿万音氏が未来人で 僕の娘とか
If that's all a fantasy, I think Okarin could
become a light novel author.
もし 全部 妄想だったら オカリン
ラノベ作家になれると思うお
I wish that were true.
そうだったら うれしいが…
You believe it, Miss Makise?
牧瀬氏 信じるん？
As a hypothesis.
仮説としてはね
If feasible, I'd prefer some reliable, objective data.
できれば 客観的データが
欲しいところだけど
But that's impossible.
それは さすがに無理だし
お前が作ったﾀｲﾑﾘｰﾌﾟﾏｼﾝの出来は
ガチだった
The time leap machine you made worked perfectly.
えっ？ あ… そ そう？
D-Did it?
あ… って とっ 当然でしょ！
O-Of course it did!
それに…
And...
What?
何よ
Nothing.
何でもない
な… 何よ～！
Wh-What?
I said nothing.
何でもないって
つなぎ終わったお
It's connected.
I need to know the settings,
but I can start in ten minutes.
うん？
設定いじらないとダメだけど
10分もしないうちに 始められる～
I'm counting on you, super haker.
頼む スーパーハカー
スーパーハッカー！
Super hacker.
ウフフッ 最初のＤメールか
The first D-mail, huh?
That's the one where I was
stabbed or whatever, right?
それって あれでしょ？
私が刺されてたとか
何とかっていう
えっ？
Did you try to feel me up or something?
それで あんた
私の体に触ろうとしたりして！
Erase all the D-mails, returning the
world line to its original one.
これまでのＤメールは
すべて 取り消し
世界線を 元に戻す
The world line in which SERN
doesn't establish a dystopia.
そこは ＳＥＲＮが支配する
ディストピアが生まれない世界線
The world line in which Mayuri doesn't die.
まゆりが死なない世界線
And in that world line...
そして… その世界線で
...Makise Kurisu...
牧瀬 紅莉栖が…
死ぬ
...dies.
お待たせしました
わー
これ シェフが悠斗のために
特別に作ってくれたんだぞ
すっごい
良かったわね 悠斗
うん